Mallory Daniel

Full Stack Developer

Portland, OR ⋈ mal@exuviae.me in LinkedIn (Github 💆 Twitter 🥆 Portfolio

PROFILE

I am a passionate, solution-oriented full stack developer with a background in sales and account management. I'm comfortable working with diverse teams and pride myself on my mid-western work ethic. I'm experienced in JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, NodeJS, (MERN), NextJS, SQL, Python, FlaskSQL, REST APIs, and Git. I'm capable of building both cohesive, interactive layouts and robust APIs to create an optimized and smooth experience for the end user.

SKILLS

HTML/CSS | JavaScript | ReactJS | Python | Bootstrap | NodeJS + Express | SQL | FlaskSQL | REST APIs Git | GitHub | MongoDB | Redux | NextJS | MongoDB | Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator) | Figma | Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Barista / Bookkeeper, Rosebridge Coffee / Fairley's Pharmacy

09/2022 - present | Portland, OR

- Serve coffee drinks & ice cream shakes
- Balance register and handle deposits, vendor POs & paying invoices
- Monthly, quarterly sales & COGS reports
- Bank statement & vendor payment reconciling

Specialty Hospital Account Manager | Software Developer, Rayne Nutrition

10/2018 - 10/2022 | Seattle, WA

- Manage top recommending veterinary specialty hospital accounts
- Discover and implement technology/programs to increase our team's efficiency and and internal communication
- Currently building a custom order approval app using ReactJS, NodeJS, Python
- Led the current top account from \$37,528/Q3 2019 to \$130,408/Q3 2021
- Improved call answer rate by Customer Care team in bringing average phone call answer rate from 67% to 85% by implementing automated processes

Assistant Manager, Mud Bay

03/2018 - 09/2018 | Maple Valley, WA

- Assisted in leading the store's creation of the Mud Bay Experience to successfully and consistently exceed over 100% of it's performance goals
- Made solution-based management decisions regarding staff and customers centered on Mud Bay's mission and values

Sales & Delivery Associate, Love Grub

07/2016 - 03/2018 | Lawrence, KS

- Created, maintained, and nurtured relationships with independent and chain retailers, new and old customers, and the community while maintaining sales and customer databases using Excel
- Transitioned company's website to SquareSpace, incorporating ecommerce and introducing online sales

EDUCATION

Evolutionary Biology & Ecology, University of Kansas

2011 - 2015

Full Stack Programming, 4Geeks Academy

11/2021

- Edie Windsor Coding Scholarship recipient

LANGUAGES

• English

PROJECTS

Co.Lab - LendA, Front End Developer

A MERN Stack CRUD app that makes lending & borrowing items within your community a smooth and easy process.

• Technologies used: ReactJS, NodeJS + Express, MongoDB, Git

Mindful Child Wellness. Website Maintenance 17

- Maintain website updates via WordPress
- Currently building a homework assignment web app